<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Sakshee Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Sakshee Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hindi text Comprehensibility</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Objective  Assess the quality of Hindi translation Check the comprehensibility of a Hindi translation  Scope This project partially addresses the translation checking bottleneck by creating a method that could be integrated into
 A set of power tools for translation consultants, which will allow them to do their checking work more thoroughly and more consistently An early warning system for translators, which will alert them to obvious problems so they can address them earlier in the translation process An equalizer for administrators and strategists, which will allow them to compare and evaluate methodologies and products (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earnings Manipulation Prediction</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Check out the live App here!
GitHub Repository
Objective  Create a user friendly tool, that can accurately classify and predict which companies are more likely to manipulate their earnings based on publicly available data. This can be an is extremely powerful tool, for not only stakeholders and investors, but also for amateur investors, with little knowledge of finance, who are just looking to reduce their risk. Provide the user with an in-depth analysis of the company data of their interest, along with a background of the research and what each predictor variable could imply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis for Trading Strategies</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Repository
Objective  To predict the market closing price based on twitter sentiment analysis. To create trading strategies for investors based on sentiment analysis.  Data  Scraped 300,000 labelled tweets for Apple, Tesla and Bitcoin from Stock Twits Sentiment for every Tweet labelled as ‘Bullish’ or ‘Bearish’.  Approach  Trained multiple deep learning models on our data to predict the sentiment of a tweet. Getting the average sentiment score for a day to predict the market for the next day  Results    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Espoir - Mental Health App</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Check out the live App here!
  GitHub Repository
  Winner for the ECS Hackathon 2021
  Background  A user-friendly Mental Health python application for companies to enhance employee welfare, by predicting employees at-risk of depression or anxiety. Designed to create a safe space for employees to deal with mental health issues, while also benefiting the company, making it a win-win situation for both! An employee can gauge their depression and anxiety levels, and follow one of the many paths we recommend as steps to move towards a healthier mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craigslist Spam Classification</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Repository
Aligning with the aim of Craigslist to increase user satisfaction, we have created an authentication categorization model which could help Craigslist in giving the users an enriched experience on the website keeping everything simple. As the False negatives are more harmful for the company, we decided on evaluating the model on precision.
Objectives  To create a model to filter spam advertisements Applying Data analysis concepts to solve the problem Enrich the user experience  Approach  Web-Sacraping Data Preprocessing Modeling Evaluation    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bankruptcy Classification</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Objective  To predict the probability of a company going bankrupt.  Approach  Importing and preprocessing the data on SAS EM. Training various models on this dataset like like Decision tree, logistic regression, neural networks etc, to find the best fit.  Performance enhancement part of these models. We did this by tuning various parameters to optimize the models in order to decrease the misclassification rate and increase the score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/education/</guid>
      <description>Purdue University, Krannert School of Management - West Lafayette, IN Master of Science in Business Analytics and Information Management GPA: 3.6/4.0
Awarded merit-based scholarship from Krannert
 1st Place in the ECS Hackathon Graduate Teaching Assistant for Business Analytics Finalist in the Crossroads Analytics Challenge VP of Operations at Graduate Women in Business VP of Marketing at Net Impact Purdue  Manipal Institute of Technology - Manipal, India Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology Minor: Big Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/experience/</guid>
      <description>Krenicki Center of Data Analytics and Machine Learning Analytics Consultant West Lafayette, IN, July 2021 - Present
 Generated insights into critical behavioral characteristics to help amplify conversion rate from customer to retail owners with Google Cloud and PySpark.  S.S. Technologies Co-founder and Product Manager Goa, India, July 2020 - January 2021
 Managed design and development of BillonFly-business management solution, transforming 10+ local businesses. Led a team of 5 developers to a finished product from ground up, by employing Agile Methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saksheeagarwal.github.io/portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Languages and Tools  Python R MySQL SAS EM Tableau Excel Ruby on Rails Java, Docker Git Google Cloud Platform C++  Core Competencies  Machine Learning Business Analytics Data Visualization Statistical Modelling Data Mining  Certifications  Tableau Analyst SAS Certified Specialist: Base Programming SAS  Non-Technical  Leadership Entrepreneurship Adaptability Critical thinking  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
